Kevin Adrián Rodríguez Ruiz

Full stack developer

About me

Chemical engineer and MEng in computing with more than four years of experience in software development.

Knowledge of web applications, Python, Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs and Amazon Web Services.

I am excited about integrating multiple disciplines and making things easier and accessible.

Interests

Web applications development. Bioinformatics. Phenomena Modelling and Optimization. Learning new engineering/science topics.

Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399 karodriguezr@unal.edu.co LinkedIn profile GitHub public repositories

SKILLS

Java, Javascript, Html, Node.js, Python, Django Framework, Reactjs, Amazon Web Services, VBA, Spring Framework, Git, VSTO Add-ins, Postgres, MongoDB, Rest, NoSQL, Scrum, Docker.

Programs: MS Excel, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

EXPERIENCE

Consultant (Amaris Consulting, 2019)

+ Oficina en línea. Full stack developer. Web application for the management of insurance policies. Technologies: Reactjs, Redux, Serverless, Amazon Web Services (Lambda, API Gateway, Redis, Dynamodb).

Software Engineer (Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, 2018 - 2019)

+ ANSEP. Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform. Design and development. Web platform for the analysis of genome-scale metabolic reconstruction related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Technologies: Python, R, Django, Reactjs, Docker, Postgresql.

Systems Analyst (Software Colombia SAS, 2015 - 2018)

- + SCmail. Design, development and maintenance. Massive email marketing platform. Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Gradle, Amazon Web Services (EC2, Lambda, S3, Dynamodb, SES, Autoscale, CodeDeploy, SQS).
- + SCmail upClient. Development and maintenance. Desktop application for the upload of directories/files from a local drive to a repository on Amazon S3. Technologies: Java, JavaFX, Amazon STS.
- + Elogic Monitor. Design, development and support. Desktop application for the generation of digital signatures, encryption, and files upload, it can be invoked from all web browsers. Technologies: Javascript, Java and JavaFX.

Academic projects (2017-2019)

- + Rescurves. Design and development. Open source MS Excel Add-in aimed to ease the three-dimensional plotting of residue curves maps for quaternary systems. Technologies: C#, VSTO.
- + Master's final work: CAMD. Design and development. Desktop application to solve the Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) problem of finding the most suitable solvent for a liquid-liquid separation. It makes use of multi-objective optimization and databases mining algorithms. Technologies: Java, Mongodb.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2019	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2018 - 2019	Exchange Student for the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Molecular Modelling Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 - 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)